Finding Aid for Arthur H. Vandenberg Papers, 1884-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound Recordings
  - Sound tape reel
    - Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg replies to recorded statements by President Franklin Roosevelt, 1936, 1 reel-to-reel audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches (Box 1)
      - [Part 1], [86746-SR-1-1]; (Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg plays recorded statements made by Franklin Delano Roosevelt and comments on issues raised. Recorded in form of debate.)
1939, October 24, 1941
Americans for Democratic Action.
July 18, 1947; June 8, 1948
Andrews, Rogert Mercein 1874-1943.
September 19, 1918 [from AHV3
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
September 13, 1915
Annenberg, Walter H., 1908-
March 11, 1948
Armour, Norman
August 4, September 12, 1947; March 20, 1948
Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1893-
March 12, April 8, 1946, July 22, 1949
Austin, Warren Robinson, 1877-1963.
March 10, March 31, May 5, 1944, May 27, 1947
Averill, George R., 1893-1971.
February 23, 1933
Baldwin, Raymond Earl, 1893-
December 3, 1948
Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.
December 7, 1920
Baruch, Bernard Marines, 1870-1965.
May 2, 1948, December 12, 1949
Bender, George Harrison, 1896-1961.
July 28, 1948
Bennett, John Bonifas, 1905-1964.
March 3, 1947
Benton, William, 1900-
November 14, 1946, October 2, 1947.
Beukema, John Charles, 1888-1967.
November 5, 1940, August 9, November 25, 1941, December 4, 1944
April 17, May 21, 1946, May 7, 1948, April 12, 1949.
Blodgett, John Wood, 1860-1951.
November 19, 1937, October 25, 1939, September 16, October 7, 1940
March 11, December 5, 1941; September 25, 1942; December 21, 1945
March 5, August 23, 1946; July 1, 1948.
Bohlen, Charles Eustis, 1904-1974.
April 23, June 11, August 30, 1948.
Bolton, Chester Castle, 1882-1939.
April 2, 1936
Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940.
August 9, 1915;December 19, 1921; September 16, 1922; March 5, 1924; April 20, 1925; July 10, 1925; April 19, 1926; September 9, 1927; July 5, 1928; July 30, 1928; August 18, 1932
Bradley, Frederick Van Ness, 1893-1947.
March 27, May 10, 1943
Brake, D., Hale, 1891-
April 22, 1949.
Bridges, Styles, 1898-
March 24, June 24, 1947
Brownell, Herbert, 1904-
September 17, September 20, September 23, 1948
Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.
June 19, 1948.
Burton, Marion LeRoy, 1874-1925-
March 27, 1920
Butler, Hugh Alfred, 1878-1954.
July 12, 1947, June 30, 1948.
Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.
December 26, 1919.
Byrnes, James Francis, 1879-
August 3, August 4, October 26, 1945; April 5, May 21, November 14, December 1, 1946; October 19, 1949.
Cain, Harry Pulliam, 1906-
September 12, 1949.
Cannon, Joseph Burney, 1836-1927.
May 10, 1919
Capehart, Homer Earl, 1897-
May 10, 1948; September 28, 1949.
Capper, Arthur, 1865-1951.
August 15, November 8, 1946.
Case, Francis Higby, 1896-1962.
January 26, 1937.
Chennault, Claire Lee, 1893-1958.
January 28, February 15, 1947.
Clay-ton, William Lockhart, 1880-1966.
April 21, June 8, June 12, 1948.
Connally, Thomas Terry, 1877-1963.
April 28, 1950.
Cooley, Mortimen Elwyn, 1855-1944.
November 8, 1932.
Coolidge, Calvin, Pres. U.S., 1872-1933.
January 26, 1926; June 18, 1928; November 14, 1928; March 8, 1924; December 31, 1924
Cooper, John Sherman, 1901-
November 14, 1949.
Copeland, Royal Samuel, 1868-1938.
February 13, 1931
Couzens, James Joseph, 1872-1936.
April 25, 1927
Cummins, Albert Baird, 1850-1926.
April 25, 1918
Curtis, Charles, 1860-1936.
November 8, 1928
Couzens, Frank, 1902-1950.
June 14, 1937.
Craig, Charles Patton, 1858-1935.
1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934.
Crowley, Leo T
October 12, 1945
Cudlip, William Byrnes, 1904-
1934, 1935, April 15, 1938, May 16, 1947, July 29, 1949.
Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951.
July 14, 1924; October 29, 1927; July 10, 1928
Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929.
August 12, 1919; February 5, 1924; April 3, 1924
Detroit Citizens League
February 15, February 19, 1938
Dewey, Thomas Edmund, 1902-1971.
August 18, 1943; March 31, April 15, May 10, May 19, May 22, 1944; July 14, December 6, 1948.
Donnell, Forrest C., 1884-
December 2, 1950.
Douglas, Paul Howard, 1892-
January 31, 1950; January 12, 1951.
Duff, James Henderson, 1883-
December 9, 1948; November 10, 1950; November 14, 1951.
Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959.
June 12, November 8, 1944;February 14, July 10, July 23, December 1945; August 14, undated, 1946; January 29, January 31, February 6, February 9, July 17, July 21, August 28, 1947
March 4, May 1, May 10, May 14, June 2, June 4, June 9, August 9, August 10, August 17, August 20, September 1948
February 4, March 29, May 2, September 16, November 10 November December 5, December 6, December 14, 1949
April 7, July 25, ;October 1950; January 8, January 9, January 17, March 1, 1951.
Eccles, Marriner Stoddard, 1890-
March 11, March 17, 1949.
Edwards, George, 1914-
March 20, June 3, June 11, August 20, 1946; June 3, 1947.
Eisenhower, Dwight David, Pres. U.S., 1890-1969.
September 14, 1949.
Fairbanks, Charles Warren, 1852-1918.
June 26, 1916
Ferris, Woodbridge Nathan, 1853-1928.
May 15, 1918 [From AHV]; February 6, 1924
Flanders, Ralph Edward, 1880-
November 24, 1948
Fletcher, Duncan Upshaw, 1859-1936.
January 3, 1936
Ford, Gerald R.
[Folder 6-7]
Forrestal, James, 1892-1949.
November 6, 1946.
Gannett, Frank Ernest, 1876-1957.
August 6, September 27, October 4, October 21, October 22, December 16, December 21, 1943; January 7, January 8, March 14, April 11, 1944.
Green, Dwight H.,1897-1958.
1944, March 12, 1945
Green, Fred Warren, 1872-1936.
May 29, 1928
Green, William, 1870-1952.
November 8, December 1, 1937; October 23, 1940; September 5, 1945; April 9, 1948.
Grew, Joseph Clark, 1880-1965.
February 16, February 20, July 9, 1945.
Harding, Warren Gamaliel, Pres. U.S., 1865-1923.
September 23, 1920; October 20, 1920; May 11, 1916
Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.
November 30, 1931
Hazlitt, Henry, 1894-
April 9, April 19, 1949.
Herring, Clyde LaVerne, 1879-1945.
June 10, September 2, September 3, October 11, 1938;April 24, 193
Herter, Christian Archibald, 1895-
February 23, 1948.
Hickenlooper, Bourke Blakemore, 1896-
August 8, 1947;October 11, 1949; January 25, 1950.
Hiss, Alger, 1904-
June 17, 1947
Hoffman, Clare Eugene, 1875-1967.
March 19, 1945
Hoover, Herbert Clark, Pres. U.S., 1874-1964
July 5, 1927; December 27, 1927; August 16, 1928; October 2, 1928; October 24, 1928; January 8, September 11, 1930; November 9:1931; June 8, July 16, July 26, July 27, August, 4, 1932; August 11, 1948; February 26, 1949
Howard, Roy Wilson, 1883-1964.
October 11, 1945
Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.
April 14, 1914, November 8, December 7, 1939; January 30, 1941; March 24, 1943; May 3, May 23, 1944; July 8, 1949.
Hurley, Patrick Jay, 1883-1963-
December 1, December 12, 1932.
Ickes, Harold L., 1874-1952.
June 28, 1935; June 5, 1942; July 22, 1947; February 11, February 11, May 14, May 21, June 29, 1948.
Jeffties, Edward J., 1900-1950.
December 6, 1939; May 19, 1947.
Johnson, Hiram Warren, 1866-1945.
August 14, 1928
Judd, Dorothy
January 17, 1941
Kendall, David Walbridge, 1903-
March 20, 1948; April 1, 1948.
Kersten, Charles J., 1902-
November 13, November 23, 1948.
Kettle, Earl
October 1, 1919 [from AHV]
Knowland, William Fife, 1908-
September 2, October 19, December 8, 1948; November 17, 1950.
Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.
July 22, 1915; July 29, 1915; July 14, 1919; August 18, 1919 [from AHV]; October T, 1928; February 29, 1928; December 20, 1929; July 29, August 19, 1932; March 25, March 31, November 29, 1938
Krock, Arthur W 1887-
November 24, 1939; November 1, 1943.
Lamont, Thomas William, 1870-
1948. December 1, 1937; July 15, 1943.
Landon, Alfred Mossman, 1887-
June 24, 1937.
Langer, William, 1886-1959.
February 23, 1948.
Lasker, Albert Davis, 1880-1952.
August 8, 1945.
Lawrence, David, 1888-1973.
July 5, 1939, November 15, 1949.
Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.
January 4, 1938, October 6, October 14, November 1, December 16, December 21, 1939; July 22, 1940; October 14, 1941; February 15 1945; February 27, March 7, March 28, April 4, April 24, May 23, 1 April 1, 1948.
Lewis, Sinclair, 1884-1951.
May 2, 1948.
Lippman, Walter, 1889-January 30, 1940
September 14, 1945; March 16, 1945; July 22, 1949; January 18, January 26, February 3, 1950.
Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902
October 22, 1920; November 1T, 1921; November 24, 1921; June 26, 1922; May 2, 1922
October 10, October 17, 1947; August 12, November 22, December 7 December 20, 1948; October 7, October 17, 1949; July 28, September October 23, 1950; February 21, 1951.
Lovett, Robert Abercrombie, 1895-
September 21, October 30, November 3, December 11, 1947; January 2, January 19, January 29, February 28, March 11, April 9, July 15, October 8, November 22, November 24, November 26, 1948; October 20, October 21, December 21, 1949; January 8, March 7, 1951.
Lucas, Scott Wike, 1892-
October 27, 1949
Luce, Henry Robinson, 1898-1967.
September 21, 1943; May 27, 1946; August 7, 1950.
MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.
October 27, 1945; June 1, June 13, 1950.
Machrowicz, Thaddeus Michael, 1899-
December 22, 1944.
Maddy, Joseph Edgar, 1891-1966.
April 20, 1949.
Marshall, George Catlett, 1880-1959.
February 4, February 10, June 24, August 8, September 29, December 11, 1947; March 22, March 25, June 11, September - October 27, 1948; October 17, November 17, 1949; July 7, September 16, December 28, 1950
McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1863-1941.
December 10, 1918; December 22, 1920; September 20, 1921; February 2T, 1922
Mellon, Andrew William, 1855-1939.
January 29, 1926
Menefee, Ferdinand Northrup, 1886-1973.
August 7, 1940.
Michener, Earl Cory, 1876-1957.
February 7, 1951.
Millikin, Eugene Donald, 1891-1958.
November 30, 1946;October 10, November 17, 1949; October 30, December 29, 1950; January 6, 1951.
Mooney, Edward, 1882-1958.
May 3, 1949.
Morse, Wayne Lyman, 1900-
November 24, 1945; November 10, 1950.
Moses, George Higgins, 1869-1944.
April 19, April 27, 1943.
Mott, Charles Stewart, 1875-1973.
April 14, 1942.
Mundt, Karl Earl, 1900-
April 3, 1945.
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
February 15, 1937.
Murrow, Edvard R., igo8-1965.
September 22, November 21, 1950.
Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.
November 17, 1941.
Norbeck, Peter, 1870-1936.
February 11, 1933.
O'Conor, Herbert Romulus, 1896-1960.
February 3, 1950.
Page, Herman, 1866-1942.
September 11, 1939.
Patterson, Robert Porter, 1891-1952.
November 12, 1946.
Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.
August 17, 1940.
Pollock, James Kerr, 1898-1968.
March 23, 1949.
Reed, Clyde Martin, 1871-1949.
January 20, 1949-
Riley, James Whitcomb, 1853-1916.
February 8, 1916
Reuther, Walter Philip, 1907-1970.
January 12, 1951.
Riggs, Henry Earle, 1865-1949.
December 22, 1936; July 29, 1937; January 21, 1939.
Rockefeller, Nelson Aldrich, 1908-
February 12, 1948; April 28, October 4, 1949.
Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.
January 6, April 16, 1947.
Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1914--
April 6, 1933, April 19, 1934; September 24, December 12, 1937; February 16, April 6, November 7, 1940; April 5, 1941; December 17, 1942; February 15, March 1, 1945.
Roosevelt, Theodore, Pres. U.S., 1858-1919.
1918?
Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-
November 14, 1949.
Scholle, August, 1904-1972.
December 9, 1946.
Schwellenbach, Levis Baxter, 1894-1948.
July 31, September 29, 1945
Scott, Hugh Daggett, 1900-
August 25, September 9, 1948.
Sloan, Alfred Pritchard, 1875-1966.
December 6, 1940.
Smith, George Otis, 1871-1944.
November 30, 1932.
Smith, Gerald Lyman Kenneth, 1898-
January 18, July 29, October 8, 1941; August 24, 1943.
Snyder, John Wesley, 1895-
February 2, 1948.
Stassen, Harold Edward, 1907-
January 21, 1949.
Stettinius, Edward Reilley, 1900-1949.
June 15, September 29, October 1, 1943; August 8, 1944; January 4, April 5, May 5, July 26, 1945.
Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.
June 22, June 23, 1949.
Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952.
December 30, 1942.
Sweet, Edwin Forrest, 184T-
December 8, 1917 [from AHV]; December 6, 191T
Taft, Charles Phelps, 1897-
November 7, November 15, 1949.
Taft, Robert Alphonso, 1889-1953.
March 29, 1944, October 20, 1946; May 26, October 6, December 2, 1947; January 19, November 4, November 11, November 22, 1950; March 26, 1951
Taft, William Howard, Pres. U.S., 1857-1930.
February 3, 1926
Thomas, Norman Mattoon, 1884-1968.
December 10, 1948; January 31, 1949.
Thomas, R.J., 1900-
February 16, 1943, September 17, 1945.
Thompson, Dorothy, 1894-1961.
December 22, 1948.
Thorp, Willard Long, 1899-
December 26, 1947.
Titus, Harold, 1888-1967.
April 7, 1943.
Toy, Harry Stanley, 1892-1955.
April 12, 1935; March 24, 1948.
Truman, Harry S., Pres. u.s.j1884-1972.
December 21, 1945, July 18, 1946; February 8, November 3, December 3, 1948; October 4, November 1, 1949
March 27, March 31, June 16, July, September 27, 1950; January 10, January 18, March 6, 1951.
Tufty, Esther (Van Wagoner)
November 7, 1946; October 5, 1949.
Vinson, Frederic Moore, 1890-1953.
October 6, 1949.
Waite, John Barker, 1882-
February 24, 1934; April 1, 1948.
Wallace, William Henry, 1861-1933.
November 15, November 19, 1932.
Warren, Earl, 1891-
October 22, 1948.
Weeks, Sinclair, 1893-
December 30, 1946.
Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961.
August 22, 1939, July 3, December 9, 1948; December 19, 1949; December 29, 1950.
Welsh, George Wilson, 1883-
July 15, August 16, 1940.
Wherry, Kenneth Spicer, 1892-1951.
January 31, February 24, 1951.
White, Wallace Humphrey, 1877-1952.
November 16, 1946.
White, Walter Francis, 1893-1955.
December 30, 1946; February 25, February 28, March 2, April
Willkie, Wendell Levis, 1892-1944.
July 15, 1941.
Winslow, Rollin
June 7, 1923
Wood, Leonard, 1860-1921.
December 21, 1918; November 30, 1919; January 20, 1920; January 25, 1920; April 16, 1920; December 9, 1920; December 15, 1920; December 27, 1920
Wood, Robert E.
Extensive correspondence, 1943, 1944.
Woodfill, William Stewart, 1896-
October 9, 1944.
Woodruff, Roy Orchard, 1876-1953.
July 21, August 4, 1944.
Ziegler, Charles M., 1888-1959.
September 14, 1944; October 31, December 7, December 26, 1945; June 6, 1946.
Index to Scrapbooks
The scrapbooks in the Arthur H. Vandenberg Collection are an invaluable series within the total collection. The scrapbooks include clippings, tear sheets from the Congressional Record, speeches, articles written by or about Vandenberg, occasional correspondence and photographs, and diary-like notes which Vandenberg himself typed and appended with the relevant clipping or speech. The following index was a compilation made by a researcher who used the scrapbooks. The index was intended for his use only, but the library requested permission to copy it and make it available to other Vandenberg scholars. The index is not as polished as it might be; some of the entries are abbreviated in note-taking fashion. Yet the result is a detailed guide to the contents of the scrapbooks. Each entry gives a page number, date of the article/item, and a brief description.
Volume I, Mar. 1928/Aug. 1929 (135 pages)
(6) - 4/?/1928, - From Congressional Record - just inserts some letters.
(8) - 5/6?/28, - speech - memorial for Senator Ferris.
(14) - 5/17/28, - "Prosperity Reserve" - Senate speech.
(20) - 5/(late)/28 - Begins reapportionment fight
(26) - 6/20/28 - letter from V.P. Charles G. Dawes.
(28) - 9/19/28 - speech (in printed form) to Republican State Convention, Detroit - defends tariff.
(31) - 7/?/28 - speech at "Air-Olympics dinner" [Detroit] (c.c.) - air power - Kellogg Treaty
(34) - 12/3/28 - AHV sworn in for short term to Mar. 4; 6 yr. term begins then.
(38B) - 12/21/28 - still pushing reapportionment. Holds up Census Bill [for 1930] until House acts on reapportionment bill. Notes House in 1921 did pass a reapportionment measure while Senate never got back from a Senate Committee. Hence, Senate much at fault.
(42) - 1/6/29 - made appeal for reapportionment on nation-wide radio hook-up "The Blue network" "Collier Hr." - copy of speech inserted in CR by Hiram Johnson 1/8/29.
(43) - 1/12/29 - beginning of Kellogg-Briand discussion
(45) - 1/11/29 - AHV typed note on his role (initiator) of the round robin to get SFRC report filed as an official interpretation of Kellogg pact. Succeeded. He drafted the R.R. circulated by Bingham.
(41/51) -- l/24/29 - Several CR pages on reapportionment included - AHV sp. on it.
(65B) - newspaper date line. AHV to go for FRC seat - states opposed to "Capper Resolution" to strengthen Kellogg Treaty.
(75) - 3/4/29 - AHV typed note on Senate rules. Filibuster had just prevented consideration of his reapportionment bill. Wants Constitution-amended to abolish Lame Duck sessions - nix "unanimous consent" frustration by one man.
(83) - 4/22/29 - AHV receives vacant seat on Senate Foreign Relations Committee.
(87) - 5/4/29 - AHV typed note on visit of H.S. class to Washington. He made speech. Group was "clean" every minute.
(88) - 5/5/29 - AHV on Tom Heflin and anti-Catholicism
(90) - 5/29 - magazine article, no id or date, Wm. A. McGarry interviewed AHV -- "Go into Politics, To Give--Not to Get"
This one tells of some of his early childhood business enterprises: push cart express service - of packing cases, etc. Bill delivery system. Comet Stamp Co. Started to write fiction in teens.
(91B) - 5/8/29 - Supports Hoover's opposition to "export debentures" (export subsidies?)
(94) - 5/15/29 - several pages of debate on apportionment begin here; ends on page 120.
(133B) - 5/14/29 - Essay on Republicanism - letter to Jackson Citizen Patriot
Volume II, Sept. 1929 - July 1930
Begin Congressional year - Sept. 1929
(2) - 9/6/29 - AHV and Senator Couzens both back R.H. Booth for diplomatic appointment. Heads a newspaper chain.
(3) - 9/--/29 - AHV leaves his publisher post. Reference to break with Governor Green (appointed to Senate) who seems planning to run for Couzens seat.
(3) - ?/29 - Protests lack of enforcement of D.C. rule on excessive auto exhaust
(4) - 9/9/29 - Flint Daily Journal. Fights tariff hike on Casein, which is much used by Kalamazoo paper mills.
(7) - 9/17/29 - Suggests Filipino (duty free) cargoes be required to be carried in U.S. ships to improve competitive position of domestic growers.
(9) - 9/14/29 -- "No Need for America to Enter World Court" essay in all Hearst newspapers.
(5B) - 9/12/29 - beginning of AHV push to limit Federal judges indirect contempt powers. From a Cleveland case where two editors were jailed for criticizing the court.
(13) - 9/21/29 More on coastal shipping laws for Philippines.
(17) - 10/19/29 American war dead buried in Russia are now being brought home. AHV pushed for it.
(18-22)-10/8/29 - AHV pushed for anti-fake antiques amendment to Tariff bill and won.
(22) - 9/24/29 - Letter to Michigan Alumnus regarding William Cook gift.
(30) - 10/21/29 - AHV typed note comparing Winston Churchill and Ramsay MacDonald, both of whom recently visited Washington. AHV prefers MacDonald. He admires Churchill's nationalism (R MacDonald's internationalism). Unfavorable reference to Churchill in Admiralty in WWI.
(31) - 10/21(?)/29 - Speech on Edison; also letter from Edison. Senate resolution. Much here on AHV's role in Tariff bill, keeps the Senate in session, etc ... very pro-Hoover.
(40-7) - 11/15/29 - AHV and "Young Guard" block adjournment and keep Senate at work on the Tariff bill.
(46) - Michigan Daily editorial commends AHV
(47) - 11/28 & 28/29 -- AHV is typed summary on chronology of "Young Turk" movement.
(49) - 12/29 - New Session begins
() - 1/19/30 dateline - first mention I have noticed of "the Wall Street Debacle" - which AHV thinks will raise opinion of Federal Reserve Reform.
(61) (see also p. 85) - 1/17/30 - AHV named to a special Commerce sub-committee to inquire into possibilities of developing a cure for cancer.
(66) - 1/29/30 dateline - More on the Philippine Independence. Speech from Congressional Record II.
(66) - 2/30 dateline - AHV designated to read Washington Farewell on Feb. 22
[AHV a member of Committee on Terrs. and Insular Affairs, which considers indefinite question]
(64) -- 1/30 - AHV opposes (in Congressional Record) raising of duty free import of American tourists returning from Canada from $100 to $200.
(70) - 2/12/30 dateline - AHV sponsors a bill to give $10,000 to the Smithsonian to buy Ethan Allen's sword (carried at the surrender of Ticonderoga), his breastplate, and another item or two.
(70-1)- 2/17/30 - Two very interesting AHV typed notes:
1. conversation with Borah: Sen. Borah & Borah-Hoover relations
2. conversation with Hoover: Hoover and Borah-Hoover relations (one part Hoover opposes recognition of Russia)
(72-3)- 2/14/30 (Congressional Record) - AHV defends the Supreme Court against Congressional attacks and attempts to subjugate.
(97) - 4/15/30 - AHV opposes purchase of the Erie Canal for he sees that move as an effort to defeat the St. Lawrence Seaway.
(104) - 5/8/30 - Letter: from American Federation of Labor President to AHV. Thanks for note against John J. Parker. Affirmation consider AHV a friend.
(105) - 5/7/30 - AHV typed note on Parker vote. Says: Senate Committee appointments are not "party" issues. Won't be a pact-nullification by one on the Supreme Court (refers to Parker's views on Negroes and implicitly 14th and 15th Amendments). "These things cannot be emphasized to the public because they would merely incite racial hostilities."
AHV handwritten note: "This experience (with my violent critics) impresses me with what a slim chance "the underdog" has in this democracy" of "equal rights" (?) These critics do not chasten me. They drive me toward liberalism. I think "the underdog" deserves a few more friends."
() - 5/20/30 - Introduces a bill for development of a "metal-clad war ship" -- already experimented; being worked on in Detroit.
(117) - 6/12/30 dateline - AHV statement text on the Senate Foreign relations Committee request for Executive papers of the London Naval Conference. Hoover refused and AHV supported Hoover.
(123B) - 6/23/30 - AHV typed note, Reflection, somewhat bitter on his fight against Erie Canal and Chicago water diversion. He won, but is bitter toward Chicago Tribune. Also Detroit Times. He says the Senate job looks good from the outside, rotten from the inside.
(133) - 8/30/30 -- Collier's article. Writer says AHV will be the next Senator to become President.
Volume III, Dec. 1930 to Nov. 1931
() - Fall 1930 - letter to Detroit Jewish Chronicle regarding "Passfield Dictim" which represents a retreat from Balfour 1917 letter. Jews and AHV upset.
(3) - 12/9/30 dateline - AHV opposes recognition of Russia.
(3) - 12/?/30 - on Kellogg, London Treaty, World Court.
(5) - 11/21/30 - Washington Star. AHV opposes bringing up World Court protocol in short session.
(5) - 11/28/30 - AHV typed note: "Just One More of Those Little Hoover Mistakes" - after Herbert Hoover has announced he will send protocol to Senate. In spite of AHV's private contrary concern. H.H. had not told AHV of change of mind - he saw it in the newspapers.
(14) - 2/5/31 - AP dateline. Hoover signs AHV bill setting 3.5 interest rate on loans to merchant marine.
(14b) - AHV letter to editor, Chicago Journal of Commerce defending his move on service certificate payments to veterans.
(15b) - 1/15/31 - AHV typed note rueing Hoover's refusal to cooperate and compromise Robinson's proposal asking for $60,000,000, (to be loaned for food and feed relief). Again, exasperation at Hoover.
(25) - 2/6/31 - Barbara Vandenberg marries John Knight of Grand Rapids.
(41) - Early Mar. 1931 - Veterans Bonus bill passed over veto. AHV on Territories Committee, soon leaving on trip to Orient (Mar. 22 to June 9, 1931) - Hawaii and Philippine - important question coming up soon. Also silver.
(41b) - 3/7/31 - Letter from Hoover. No consequence.
() - 6/20/31 dateline. AHV supports Hoover's debt moratorium. Again calls for moratorium regarding own sinking fund.
Volume IV, Fall 1931 - July 1932
(1) - Synopsis sheet
(4) - 9/10/31 - Letter to Hoover
(9b) - 12/7/31 - AHV becomes grandfather